JOSH HARGETT

415 Charidges Drive, Houston, TX 77034 · 504-628-7022

Joshhargett.jh@gmail.com · https://github.com/jhargett1

https://medium.com/@joshhargett.jh

As an Azure certified Cloud Engineer with 6 years of system engineer experience, I have developed a strong foundation in troubleshooting and problem-solving. With a focus on automation and optimization, I have consistently demonstrated my ability to identify potential problems before they occur, minimizing downtime and improving system performance. I am excited to bring my abilities and passion for cloud technology to your organization to help drive success and achieve business objectives.

EXPERIENCE

2/2023 - PRESENT

CLOUD ENGINEER, THEJOSHDEV.COM(STILL IN PROGRESS)

https://github.com/jhargett1/aws-bootcamp-cruddur-2023

Created micro-blogging platform for Cloud Project Bootcamp hosted by AWS hero Andrew Brown. The application allows you to login, create a new post, send DMs, and edit a user profile.

- Frontend application written in Javascript using React, while the backend application written in Python using Flask.
- Was able to containerize entire application using Docker, AWS ECS, and AWS ECR.
- Provided data to application utilizing Postgres SQL and DynamoDB implemented via AWS RDS
- Utilized AWS CDK to implement avatar uploading resources served via CloudFront
- Managed to implement CI/CD pipeline via AWS CodePipeline andCodeBuild
- Re-implemented application in IaC using AWS CloudFormation
- Web application is the first ephemeral micro-blogging platform of its kind with expiring posts

06/2020 - PRESENT

SYSTEM ENGINEER, THE MILLER GROUP

System Engineer role in an MSP environment. I multitask and respond to assigned service requests while respecting SLA.

- Provided Office 365/Azure administration & maintenance to over 200 MSP clients
- Completed PC and Server maintenance requests via alerts handed down by Datto RMM
- Responded to user inquiries regarding remote troubleshooting and diagnosis of hardware, software, network, and printing problems

07/2019 - 06/2020

PC LIFECYCLE MANAGEMENT, BAYER-MONSANTO

Part of Lifecycle Team Management providing onsite assistance to users with Windows 10 conversions as part of Bayer-Monsanto merger.

- Exported user .pst files from PCs along with OneDrive backups then re-implemented on freshly installed Windows 10 PCs
- Assisted users with any pending questions/concerns
- Converted roughly 90-95% of St. Louis userbase, an estimated 4400 employees

04/2019 - 07/2019

HELP DESK ADMINISTRATOR, ALTER TRADING

Performed administrative tasks and responded to user inquiries in timely manner.

- Provided Tier I/II support for userbase of roughly 400 employees
- Assisted in implementation of software upgrades/installations, network configurations, and minor fixes to in house application via Microsoft SCCM

03/2017 - 04/2019

TEAM LEAD, INTELLITEACH (NOW KNOWN AS FRONTLINE MANAGED SERVICES)

Multiple roles within managed service provider environment for lawfirms. Started as Service Desk Analyst, then Senior Service Desk Analyst, working my way up to Team Lead

- Provided Tier I/II remote support for 100s of lawfirms worldwide
- In leadership, assisted with implementation of new firm/project rollouts

EDUCATION AND COURSEWORK

2009

.NET DEVELOPMENT COURSE, CENTRIQ TRAINING

This was a 6-month course teaching us how to develop in the .NET Framework using C#.

2005

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA, SOUTH GRAY HIGH SCHOOL

CERTIFICATIONS

EXPIRES 2023

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT EXPERT, MICROSOFT

Earned on: 12/18/2022

EXPIRES 2023

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE ADMINISTRATOR ASSOCIATE, MICROSOFT

Earned on: 12/18/2022

DOES NOT EXPIRE

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE FUNDAMENTALS, MICROSOFT

Earned on: 10/27/2022

ACTIVITIES

In my free time I am a big fan of staying active with the gym, spending time with my wife and 2 dogs, and watching true crime documentaries.